



# **Leo Hajder**

**Date of birth:** 14 Nov 1987 | **Nationality:** Croatian | **Gender:** Male | **Phone number:** 

(+385) 918977786 (Mobile) | Email address: <a href="mailto:leohajder@gmail.com">leohajder@gmail.com</a> | Website:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/leohajder/ | Website: https://github.com/leohajder | Website:

https://leohajder.github.io/ Address: Put Supavla 28, 21000, Split, Croatia (Home)

### ABOUT ME

I am a software developer mostly based in PHP and the Symfony framework. I also have a good working knowledge of Sylius and Ibexa CMS and am currently gaining more experience with API Platform. I am also capable of performing basic to intermediate tasks with JavaScript, Node.js, Python and CSS.

I have about eight years of professional experience in working on several projects of varying size, age and condition while collaborating with people from all departments, including direct communication with clients and product owners.

I enjoy building new solutions and integrating systems via APIs while using current best practices and writing clean code. I like to optimize early enough to make the code faster and more readable, but not too soon to lose perspective of the issue at hand or overengineer the solution.

I can work in a team and by myself, share my knowledge and mentor my coworkers, and I am always open to give and receive constructive feedback and improve myself and the team as a whole.

I would describe myself as open to all people and experiences. It is never a bad idea to learn something new. You may find me funny sometimes, and I believe any day is better if you find something to smile about.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

1 FEB 2020 - CURRENT Zagreb, Croatia

### **BACKEND DEVELOPER NETGEN**

This is my current and longest-lasting position to date. I developed a high level of trust and respect among my colleagues, learned quite a lot, and became much more independent and skilled. I work on much more projects simultaneously than ever before, which helped me switch contexts more easily. I often communicate directly with clients, which helped me improve my soft skills and allowed me to meet many people in the industry and expand my professional network.

I have the opportunity to work on many large and complex projects, mostly focusing on Ibexa CMS and our open source extensions and tools. Through this, I am able to contribute to the company and the community, as well as to get more in-depth knowledge of the codebase. I expanded my working knowledge to all areas across the stack, including protocols, caching, concurrent, locking and asynchronous code execution, search engines, complex business logic, etc. My interest in code architecture, extensibility, and efficiency has developed even further. To list some technologies, I have gained experience with Symfony Command, Messenger, and Process components, RabbitMQ, JavaScript promises, AJAX requests, Solr, Algolia, etc.

I have both given and received lots of code reviews, knowledge sharing opportunities, and constructive feedback, which has made me a much better developer and mentor. As my experience and responsibilities have grown considerably over my time here, I believe I am progressing towards a higher level of seniority. I also learned to handle stressful situations and tight deadlines much better.

Address Savska cesta 182, 10000, Zagreb, Croatia | Website https://netgen.io/

1 APR 2019 - 7 FEB 2020 Zagreb, Croatia

**BACKEND DEVELOPER MOJPOSAO (TAU ONLINE)** 

Among other tasks, I was given a co-tech lead position on a multisite multitenant backend API that is consumed by several frontend and mobile applications. Because of this, we focused heavily on authorization, authentication, and access control, using JWT tokens and complex roles and policies.

The company decided to try a new stack, which meant I had to switch to writing code in Node.js using Nest.js. I also took over a project written in Python using Django. I also continued maintaining my chatbot project written in PHP using Symfony.

This helped me become proficient in several stacks enough to perform everyday tasks and switch contexts frequently, gain insights into different coding styles and approaches, and get to use a wide array of technologies.

I was given the opportunity to mentor and lead junior colleagues, assign tasks, perform code reviews, and hold knowledge sharing sessions.

Website https://mojposao.hr/

1 SEP 2017 - 31 MAR 2019 Zagreb, Croatia

### **JUNIOR DEVELOPER MOJPOSAO (TAU ON-LINE)**

I started doing most of my tasks unsupervised, greatly increasing my ability to write clean code, test my solutions, and give better estimates and feedback to product owners.

I was given the opportunity to develop a midsize project that included chatbots for Facebook and Viber, connected to several APIs in order to parse users' messages, extract information relevant to job positions they might be searching for, query the search engine and the database, and build graphical carousels with the search results. The project also had an admin interface for a semi-automatic assisted learning engine, which is used to provide custom replies to certain messages as well as match predefined job positions from the given text.

I developed the whole application, including parsing text messages and consuming several job posting sources via APIs, frontend templates, and javascript. Some of the technologies I used were PHP, Symfony, MySQL, MongoDB, iQuery, and Bootstrap.

Because the project required good organization of code and separation of logic, I developed an interest in code architecture and design patterns, which helped in maintaining the project readable and easily extendable. I also began sharing my knowledge with my colleagues much more.

Website https://mojposao.hr/

1 NOV 2016 – 31 MAY 2017 Zagreb, Croatia

#### **JUNIOR BACKEND DEVELOPER HUMAN**

I gained my first working experience and learned what it was like to work as a software developer in general. I encountered real-life projects and everyday situations on a much bigger scale.

I participated in meetings and learned to communicate with project managers, product owners, and other developers in a detailed and concise manner. That included discussions on tasks until the whole team gathered all the information critical to understanding the issue at hand, dividing the problem into smaller tasks, solving them, and reporting back to the client.

I received invaluable mentorship from more experienced colleagues, which helped me improve the quality of my code and problem-solving skills greatly.

I contributed mainly by bugfixes and smaller features on in-house frameworks and business logic, under constant supervision.

Website <a href="https://www.humaninteraction.com/">https://www.humaninteraction.com/</a>

#### EDUCATION AND TRAINING

1 SEP 2003 - JUN 2007 Split, Croatia

HIGHSCHOOL GRADUATE 3. gimnazija

#### LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): CROATIAN

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production Spoken interaction		
ENGLISH	C1	C1	C1	C1	C1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

### **COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS**

# **Proficient English**

I am proficient in English in speaking and writing, using adequate register and degree of formality to suit all scenarios of communication with coworkers, clients, and other personnel in the business context. I am able to discuss all phases of software development, including technical details, task administration, code reviews, gathering information from clients to ensure optimal understanding of features and issues, providing accurate feedback, and anything else that may arise in a working environment.

## Ability to work in a team and by myself

I consider myself capable of performing an array of tasks both as a member of a team and by myself. I approach my work with great responsibility and care for the quality of the end product.

I believe I will display adequate levels of professionalism and expertise while performing my tasks, discussing ideas for solutions, giving and receiving feedback, etc. Also, I strongly believe that any potential issues, roadblocks, unforeseen circumstances, and such should be communicated as early as possible to find the best way to address them and continue working smoothly.

### Willingness to fit in

I always do my best to help my coworkers and the company as a whole, present them in a positive light, conduct myself professionally, and look to bring cohesion to the team in all situations.

### MANAGEMENT AND LEADERSHIP SKILLS

# Mentoring students and interns

At my current company, I was given an opportunity to mentor and supervise a group of internship students while working on a project which will be used internally to create and organize a digital knowledge base by uploading videos of knowledge sharing sessions, assigning tags and categories, dividing into chapters, transcribing, translating the transcripts, etc.

I held daily standup meetings, helped guide brainstorming sessions, discussions about solutions, and personal performance reviews. I also provided code reviews and tried my best to give detailed explanations for all change requests while enforcing the best practices regarding clean code.

I am proud to say the company has decided to offer all the interns part-time work-and-study contracts, and I would like to think that my guidance has helped them in that achievement. I would gladly participate in such activities again if an opportunity presents itself.

#### ORGANISATIONAL SKILLS

### **Assisting in conference organization**

My current company being the main driving force behind Web Summer Camp, I am always happy to help organize, facilitate, and run the events. This includes working on the registration desk, helping with equipment setup, providing information to speakers and attendees, and running errands.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

### Working knowledge of technologies

PHP, Symfony, Ibexa, Sylius, JavaScript, Node.js, Nest.js, Python, Django, MySQL, MongoDB, DoctrineORM, Git

### HONOURS AND AWARDS

14 NOV 2022

Symfony 6 certificate - SensioLabs

Links <a href="https://leohajder.github.io/docs/symfony\_6\_certificate.pdf">https://leohajder.github.io/docs/symfony\_6\_certificate.pdf</a> | <a href="https://connect.symfony.com/profile/leohajder">https://connect.symfony.com/profile/leohajder</a>

24 NOV 2016

MTA Software Development Fundamentals certificate - Microsoft

Link https://www.credly.com/badges/4fbde96e-cd6b-48d1-8af1-38cf88980272/linked\_in\_profile

1 MAR 2007

**CAE certificate - University of Cambridge, ESOL Examinations** 

### DRIVING LICENCE

**Driving Licence:** AM **Driving Licence:** B